<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jaishree&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://JaishreeJanu.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jaishree&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 12:46:03 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://JaishreeJanu.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Linear versus nonlinear phenomena, their relationship, and algorithmic approaches</title>
      <link>https://JaishreeJanu.github.io/posts/linear_vs_nonlinear/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 12:46:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JaishreeJanu.github.io/posts/linear_vs_nonlinear/</guid>
      <description>Linear versus nonlinear phenomena When the change in the output of a system is directly proportional to the change in input, the system exhibits a linear phenomenon. All other phenomena are nonlinear. Linear phenomena are much simpler and coherent than nonlinear phenomena. Maxwell’s theory of Electromagnetism [1] is a linear phenomenon. Millions of electromagnetic signals travel in space among cell phones through satellites, but they don’t interfere with each other. The data and videos sent via the signals are neither lost nor created during the transmission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Data Structures and Algorithms obsolete today in the age of Machine Learning?</title>
      <link>https://JaishreeJanu.github.io/posts/ds_and_ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 12:04:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://JaishreeJanu.github.io/posts/ds_and_ml/</guid>
      <description>Data Structures and Algorithms In order to solve a computer science problem, we need a set of instructions (an algorithm) that operate on certain input data and produce some output data. Data structures provide efficient storage and efficient access, and modification of data in a computer’s memory [1]. Data Structures and Algorithms are the key foundations required to solve any computer science problem efficiently. Whereas Machine Learning is a powerful medium to solve today’s problems using data, which under the hood is the consumer of data structures and algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
